Cook, Alice Papers /3012
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series Series I: Correspondence
  - Pem-Per, 1955-1967 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Correspondence with Mark Perlman (John's Hopkins University); Selig Perlman (University of Wisconsin) regarding professional and personal; other routine.
  - Perkins, Frances, 1956-1967 (Box 2, Folder 29-32)
    And undated. Correspondence regarding plans for her visit to Cornell as visiting lecturer (Alice Cook asked by Dean Catherwood to represent him and the faculty regarding the invitation); housing/lodging arrangements, proposals regarding teaching assignments, administrative matters, writing and research, plans for book on Al Smith, personal, and other related documents.
  - Pet, 1958-1969 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Recommendations; with Esther Peterson (Amalgamated Clothing Workers, US Department of Labor) regarding mutual interests, Korean labor movement, guest lecturer and other matters; and other routine
  - Ph-Pol, 1955-1966 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    With Prof. Eric Polisar regarding proposed conference, 22 page manuscript (untitled), AFSCME draft constitution and other related documents
  - Pon-Pu, 1958-1969 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Considerable amount of correspondence with Father Basil Price (Soqsuq Jesuit College, Seoul, Korea) regarding setting up an Institute for Labor and Management, grant requests, budget and mutual interests; other related
  - Q, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Ra-Rep, 1955-1970 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    With consultants of Radcliff College regarding Alice Cook assisting and advising them in publishing a biographical dictionary of American women; and routine
  - Ret-Riv, 1954-1973 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    Correspondence with Victor Reuther (UAW) regarding class speakers and other interests; administrative correspondence with Robert Risley (ILR, Acting Dean); and other routine.
  - Rob-Rog, 1956-1971 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    With Congressman Howard T. Robison; with Lawrence Roqin regarding personal, career, labor relations field and other related matters; and other routine.
  - Rol-Ru, 1955-1971 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    Recommendations; editorial correspondence with Henry Rutz (AFL-CIO); and other routine.
  - Sa, 1959-1972 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    Includes 6 page letter from Bernard Samoff commenting on her articles on dual government; with Leonard Sandman (American Embassy, Seoul, Korea) regarding personal & professional; recommendations; and other routine.
  - Sch-Schr, 1955-1971 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    Recommendations; correspondence with former student Ruth Schimel regarding her career and other matters; and other routine
  - Schu-Schw, 1956-1970 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    Correspondence with Roaslind Schulman, personal & professional; and other routine.
  - Sco-Se, 1958-1972 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    Recommendations; correspondence with former students; other routine
  - Sha-She, 1959-1974 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    Recommendations; with Al Shanker (United Federation of Teachers) regarding various matters of mutual interest; and other routine
  - Shimada, Haruo, 1956-1969 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    (Alice Cook's assistant at Keio University) includes considerable amount of correspondence regarding obtaining research materials for Alice Cook's study on Japanese labor unions, his application to Cornell University and other matters.
  - Shim-Sie, 1957-1968 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Sil-Sl, 1956-1969 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    With Louis Silverberg (US Embassy, Tokyo) regarding professional & personal; with William & Ruth Simkin regarding his appointment as head of Federal Conciliation Service Center, John F. Kennedy and other mutual interests; with Fanny Simm (Mexico) regarding adult education materials and other person & routine; recommendations; and other routine
  - Sm, 1961-1969 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    Recommendations; correspondence, personal & professional with Hilda W. Smith and a 17 page manuscript "A Review of My Experience with the Organized Labor Movement" by Smith; other routine.
  - Sn-So, 1958-1972 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Sp-Sta, 1958-1968 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    Recommendations; personal & professional correspondence with Prof. Karl R, Stadler (Austria & Germany) regarding research, travels and other mutual interests; with Mark Starr (Esporanto League for North America) regarding research, mutual acquaintances and interests; and other routine.
  - Ste, 1958-1971 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    Recommendations; considerable amount of correspondence with Roger Stetter former student, regarding his career, discussion of the racial problems at Cornell University (1969); and other routine
  - Sti-Sw, 1956-1969 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    With Prof. Jack Stieber (Michigan State University) regarding his study of public employee unions and other matters; recommendations; and other routine.
  - Ta, 1960-1973 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    With Prof. Philip Taft (Brown University); with Japanese student Shintaro Takahashi regarding his course of study and obtaining necessary documents for family to come to US; and other routine.
  - Te, 1958-1972 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    Recommendations; with Alan Teck, former student, regarding his career and mutual interests; and other routine.
  - Th-Tr, 1955-1970 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    Personal correspondence with Adelheid Troescher (Germany); and other routine.
  - Ts-Ty, 1955-1971 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    Recommendations; with Prof. Yoshi Tsurmi (Queens University) regarding Japan labor relations, personal and other related; with Herbert Tulatz (ICFTU, Germany) regarding editorial, personal and other common interests; with Gus Tyler (ILGWU) regarding book review by Alice Cook; and other related.
  - Ul-Und, 1959-1971 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    With Vidkunn Ulriksson (American Embassy, Sweden) regarding visit to School and editorial matters; and other routine
  - United Federation of Teachers, 1965-1971 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    Correspondence regarding collecting documents for her study regarding teachers (unions in government employment) and arranging interview with union members; and other related
  - Une-Up, 1955-1968 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    With Mildred Jeffrey and others of UAW regarding personal & Professional; with Walter Reuther (UAW) regarding effort to mobilize a National Citizens Crusade Against Poverty and other matters; and other routine
  - V, 1954-1969 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    Recommendations; with Betty Vaughn (Syracuse University) regarding Alice Cook's gift of books to Syracuse Library on adult education in Germany; other routine.
  - Washenheim, Hedwig, 1955-1969 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    Generally personal correspondence regarding visits, conference, writings and many other issues of mutual interests
  - Wak-Wal, 1959-1970 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Wan-Wat, 1954-1973 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    With Colston Warne (President, Consumers Union) regarding personal and professional; and other routine
  - We-Wei, 1956-1971 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    Recommendations; with Abe Weiss (International leather Workers Union) visiting lecturer, personal & professional; with Morris Weisz (US Embassy, New Delhi, India) regarding contributing to a volume of essays in honor of David J. Saposs, personal & professional; and other routine
  - Wer-Wh, 1955-1978 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    Includes a 18 page report on Chile and Peru by WF Whyte and JM Stycos; other routine
  - Wil-Wine, 1954-1972 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    routine
  - Windmuller, John, 1955-1967 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    Includes administrative departmental (ILR) matters; his sabbatic in Switzerland; and many other issues
  - Wit-Wol, 1955-1972 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    With Prof. Wolff (New York University) regarding editorial; other routine
  - Woo-Wu, 1957-1971 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Ya-Yoe, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    Includes correspondence and holiday greeting card from Ichiro Yamamoto (Japan); recommendations; and other routine
  - Yok-Yw, 1955-1969 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Z, 1957-1972 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    With Billie Zamir (Israel) discusses visits to Israel, other personal & professional matters; other routine
  - Miscellaneous unidentified (Box 2, Folder 74)
- Series Series II: Academic Files
  - Sub-Series A. Committee Files (ILR & Cornell University)
    - Academic Standards - Common, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Includes minutes and memos
    - Advisory Committee - Work & Family (CU), 1994-1998 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Includes minutes, recommendations, policies, and related documents
    - Advisory Committee - Labor Management Documentation Center, 1956-1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Includes minutes, memos and related materials
    - Advisory Council ILR School, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Memos from Provost Robert A. Plane
    - American Association of University Professors (AAUP) Committee on Academic Freedom-CU Chapter, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
      Includes reports, memos, minutes, correspondence and related documents
    - AAUP CU Chapter Executive Committee, 1965-1972 (Box 3, Folder 7-10)
      Correspondence, memos, officials statements, minutes, reports and related documents
    - Appeals Committee CU Legislation, 1981-1989 (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
      Memos regarding procedure review and other related documents
    - Career Center Study Groups - Women, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      Memos and miscellaneous
    - Centennial Convocation Committee - CU, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 14-18)
      Includes minutes, memos, correspondence regarding planning events for the celebration
    - Committee Disadvantage Students, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Committee on Children, Work & Family CU, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
      Includes, proposals, reports, minutes, memos, recommendations and other related.
    - Committee on Extension (ILR), 1960-1964 (Box 3, Folder 22-24)
      Reports, recommendations, memos, minutes, proposals and other related material.
    - Committee Reports CU Miscellaneous Keast, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      Reports
    - Cornell Journal of Female Studies - Editorial Board, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Cornell University Grievance Review Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      Regarding grievance of dining worker- dismissed
    - Cornell University Senate, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      Memos
    - Curriculum Committee (ILR Undergraduate), 1956-1960 (Box 3, Folder 29-31)
      Memos, reports, minutes and related materials
    - Emerson, Eleanor - Intern Committee, 1964-1972 (Box 3, Folder 32-36)
      Includes mane letter and contributions from acquaintances of Eleanor Emerson for her letterbook at her retirement as well as financial contributions towards the intern program - also memos, draft letters and other related committee materials.
    - Faculty Committee for Scheduling Public Events CU, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 37-38)
      Reports, minuets and memos
    - Faculty Committee ILR School Discussions, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 39)
      Includes memos, proposals reports, working papers regarding undergraduate education and related issues; includes 7 page report by Alice Cook regarding employment of ILR grades.
    - Faculty Committee Reports CU, 1958-1964 (Box 3, Folder 40-43)
      Copies of reports and memos (mostly faculty council) on many subjects collected by Alice Cook as a member of the faculty (not necessarily as a member of a committee).
    - Faculty Committee Reports CU, 1967-1972 (Box 3, Folder 44-45)
      Same as above
    - Faculty Legislation CU, 1955-1971 (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
      Reports, minutes, resolutions, by-laws
    - Faculty Minutes CU, 1960-1972 (Box 4, Folder 5-9)
      Minutes
    - Graduate School CU, 1963-1972 (Box 4, Folder 10-12)
      Reports, minutes and related
    - Home Economics Search Committee, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      Correspondence and memos regarding search for Extension Leader position
    - Human Rights Committee CU, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 14-15)
      Includes reports, proposals, hand written notes, memos, minutes and related
    - Institute of Public Employees Relations Advisory Board, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      Request from Robert Doherty for her to serve on an informal advisory board.
    - International Affairs Committee (ILR), 1955-1965 (Box 4, Folder 17-23)
      Includes papers, reports, memos and proposals
    - International Committee Activities, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      Minutes and memos
    - Issues in Industrial Society Temporary Advisory Board, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 25)
      Memos and related materials
    - Jeffrey (Newman) Project Advisory Committee, 1958-1963 (Box 4, Folder 26-27)
      Correspondence, reports, and proposals.
    - Language Board, Graduate CU, 1961-1968 (Box 4, Folder 28-31)
      Policy statements, reports, memos, minutes and other related documents
    - Long Range Planning Committee (ILR School), 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 32-33)
      Includes drafts on the mission of the ILR School
    - Middle East Project ILR, 1958-1960 (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
      Many reports regarding these unions in the middle east sent to the Committee by Allan Snyder as part of his grant/study project, discusses situations in Iraq, Lebanon, Jordan and other area in great detail
    - MILR Exam Committee, 1957-1968 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
      Includes copies of exams and papers submitted to Committee and other related
    - Minority Education Committee CU, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Proposed changes, memos
    - Nominating Committee CU, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Pierce Lectureship Series Committee, 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      Memos/correspondence regarding plans for lectures
    - Public Employee Relations, Ad Hoc Committee, 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Statler Club Board, 1961-1972 (Box 5, Folder 10-13)
      Includes newsletter, by-laws, memos, reports and other related documents
    - Status of Women Advisory Committee CU, 1984-1994 (Box 5, Folder 14-15)
      Regarding pay equity and other issues, and reports
    - Summers (Clyde) Committee, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      Group of ILR Faculty asked to give advice and suggestions to Summers who chaired the New York State Governor's Committee on Improper Labor and Management Practices memos, notes and other related materials.
    - United Transportation Union Project Committee, 1969-1972 (Box 5, Folder 17-18)
    - University Lectures Committee, 1957-1962 (Box 5, Folder 19-20)
      Minutes, reports, correspondence and other related documents
    - University Search Committee - Senior Professorship, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      Alice Cook member of search committee to make nominations for the John L. Senior Chair
    - Visitors, Lecturers Committee ILR, 1957-1960 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      Memos regarding suggested visitors, lists, minutes procedures and other related.
    - Women, Status of Committee CU, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 23-25)
      Regarding continuing education for women, affirmative action and other issues Includes reports, questionnaire, memos and notes
    - Young Socialist League CU Advisor, 1964-1969 (Box 5, Folder 26-28)
      Broadsides, announcements, memos, clippings, policy booklet and other related documents.
  - Sub-Series B. Departmental Files (ILR & CU)
    - Associate Degree Program NYC, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      Report and related materials
    - Audio Visual Department, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Center for International Studies CU, 1965-1971 (Box 5, Folder 31-32)
      Includes memos, statements, proposals and other related materials on Center activities
    - Constituent Assembly CU, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 33)
      Memos, statement regarding CU Senate proposal
    - Department of Collective Bargaining, Labor Law and Labor Movements, 1956-1972 (Box 5, Folder 34-38)
      Includes departmental meeting minutes, memos, reports, regarding teaching assignments, staffing needs, courses, visiting professors and guest speakers, course offerings in New York, and other departmental activities and issues
    - Department of International and Comparative Labor Relations, 1962-1970 (Box 5, Folder 39-43)
      Includes minutes, memos, correspondence, regarding course descriptions, guest lecturers, staffing needs, and other administrative activities
    - Extension Division AFL-CIO Community Services Consumer Education Program, 1956-1963 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
      Correspondence, memos, and related materials regarding the program offered by Extension
    - Extension Division Batavia I.U.E. Class, 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Includes report, outline and memos
    - Extension Division Buffalo, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Extension Division Conference of Educational Methods, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Memos, and other related documents
    - Extension Division Education Conference Communication Workers, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Conference materials
    - Extension Division Health, Industrial, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Includes articles and papers regarding health, health insurance
    - Extension Division I.B.E.W. Local 3, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Correspondence and class materials, course outlines, and notes
    - Extension Division IUIEC Final Report, 1954-1957 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Correspondence, mailing lists, summary and other related materials
    - Extension Division Local 342, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      Materials regarding Women's Division Conference
    - Extension Division Local Unions, 1956-1969 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Miscellaneous papers, reading lists, outlines, notes
    - Extension Division Local Unions Communications, 1953-1961 (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
      Reports, notes, memos, outlines, publications and other related documents
    - Extension Division Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen (Box 6, Folder 14)
      Regarding Community Affairs Programs in the local lodges - outlines, reading list; no date
    - Extension Division Materials Project (Brooks and GAMM), 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      Newsletters
    - Extension Division Mayors and County Officers, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Miscellaneous materials
    - Extension Division New York City, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Extension Division NILE Program, 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      Outlines, reports, memos, notes, and related materials
    - Extension Division, 1957-1964 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      Memos, correspondence, minutes, regarding general and administrative departmental issues
    - Extension Division, 1965-1985 (Box 6, Folder 20-21)
      Memos, correspondence, minutes, regarding general and administrative departmental issues, also includes a 19-page paper by William F. Whyte entitled "ILR Extension: From 1985 to 2000."
    - Extension Division Off Campus Credit Courses, 1967-1970 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      Memos regarding courses
    - Extension Division Poverty Project, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      Project materials
    - Extension Division Printing Pressmen Buffalo Meeting, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      Correspondence, conference materials
    - Extension Division Printers, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 25)
      Memos and workshop materials
    - Extension Division Puerto Rico Program, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      Correspondence, reports, lecture notes for Labor Education Training Program at University of Puerto Rico
    - Extension Division Reports, 1963-1971 (Box 6, Folder 27-30)
      Division Reports
    - Extension Division State, County and Municipal Workers, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Extension Division UFT Arden House, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 32)
      Information regarding leadership program
    - Extension Division UFT Training Session (Box 6, Folder 33)
      no date; routine
    - Extension Division Women, 1968-1970 (Box 6, Folder 34)
      Correspondence and related materials regarding plans for a program on working women as well as other projects relating to women
    - Human Resources CU Services, 1992-1997 (Box 6, Folder 35)
      Articles, memos, and related documents regarding activities, policies, benefits and other issues
    - ILR Alumni, 1960-1970 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Includes a survey and memos regarding school alumni
    - ILR Faculty Graduate, 1955-1969 (Box 7, Folder 2-3)
      Includes minutes, memos regarding assistantship assignments, requirements for degrees, policies and procedures, and other related issues
    - ILR Faculty Legislation, 1969-1971 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Regarding revisions and proposed changes
    - ILR Faculty, 1959-1972 (Box 7, Folder 5-9)
      Memos and reports regarding procedures, lists, curriculum, course evaluation, student records, planning, committee elections, budget and many other administrative issues
    - ILR Faculty Minutes, 1966-1971 (Box 7, Folder 10-12)
      Copies of minutes of regular faculty meetings
    - ILR Faculty Reports, 1963-1971 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      Annual reports (Cook)
    - ILR Institute for Labor Market Policies, 1989-1992 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      Memos regarding the establishment of the Center and related materials
    - ILR News, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      Scattered issues of school publication
    - ILR Review, 1954-1971 (Box 7, Folder 16-18)
      Memos and correspondence regarding administrative and editorial matters, minutes and other related materials
    - ILR Student Government, 1958-1962 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - International Affairs Department, 1964-1966 (Box 7, Folder 20)
      Includes reports of the Cornell/AID Project (Chile)
    - Library ILR, 1962-1971 (Box 7, Folder 21-22)
      Memos with library staff requesting publications and other issues
    - Minority Studies ILR, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 23)
      Regarding proposal for a Center for Minority Studies
    - N.Y.C. Semester, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 24)
      Proposal and report regarding junior semester in N.Y.C.
    - Office of Resident Instruction ILR, 1962-1972 (Box 7, Folder 25-27)
      Memos, correspondence, lists, etc. regarding jobs, applications, scholarships, assistantships, and other related issues and activities
    - Office of Resident Instruction ILR, 1962-1967 (Box 7, Folder 28)
      Annual Reports of Placement Activities
    - Ombudsman CU, 1969-1971 (Box 7, Folder 29)
      Annual Reports
    - Oral History Department CU, 1965-1971 (Box 7, Folder 30)
      Memos and bulletins regarding various ILR projects in the department
    - Research and Publications Division ILR, 1960-1972 (Box 7, Folder 31-33)
      Reports, memos regarding financial support, projects and other issues and activities
    - Review Committee ILR (Tenure), 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 34)
      Memos regarding activities of the Committee
    - Social Science Research Center CU, 1956-1966 (Box 7, Folder 35)
      Memos regarding various programs, workshops, grants and reports
    - Working Women Institute, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 36-37)
      Proposals for Institute, notes and memos
  - Sub-Series C. Administrative Files - Research Project Files
    - Japan Research, 1962-1969 (Box 8, Folder 1-7)
    - Research Government Employment, 1964-1968 (Box 8, Folder 8-12)
    - Research Support General, 1968-1971 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Sub-Series D. Teaching Files
    - Sub-Series 1. Class Materials
      - Sub-Series a. Lecture Notes
        - Labor and Politics ILR 200 (Box 8, Folder 14-15)
        - Labor History: To The AFL, 1881 (Box 8, Folder 16)
        - Labor History: The AFL to 1914 (Box 8, Folder 17)
        - Labor History: WWI New Deal (Box 8, Folder 18)
          History of Bargaining to 1935
        - Labor History: New Deal, 1933-1938 (Box 8, Folder 19)
        - Labor History: WWII Taft-Hartley, 1939-1947 (Box 8, Folder 20)
        - Labor History: Taft-Hartley Laudrum-Griffin, 1947-1957 (Box 8, Folder 21)
        - Labor History: The 1960s, 1951-1964 (Box 8, Folder 22)
        - Law (Box 8, Folder 23)
        - Law - 300 (Box 8, Folder 24)
        - Politics - 605 (Box 8, Folder 25)
        - Structure Collective Bargaining (Box 8, Folder 26)
        - Trade Unionism Public Policy Theory (Box 8, Folder 27)